<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learning Monk Blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learning Monk Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© learning-monk.github.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis: Air Quality in India</title>
      <link>/posts/analysis-air-quality-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/analysis-air-quality-in-india/</guid>
      <description>.myCode {background-color: black;color: white;}Source of the Data:
https://www.kaggle.com/rohanrao/air-quality-data-in-india?select=city_day.csv
Process of calculating air quality index:
https://www.kaggle.com/rohanrao/calculating-aqi-air-quality-index-tutorial
What are the safe limits of these pollutants in air for India?
http://www.arthapedia.in/index.php?title=Ambient_Air_Quality_Standards_in_India
About the Dataset:The dataset has air quality readings of major India cities for the period 2015-2020.
This dataset captures the air quality parameters of PM2.5, PM10, Nitrogen Oxide (NO), Nitrogen Dioxide (NO2), Ammonia (NH3), Carbon Monoxide (CO), Sulphur Dioxide (SO2), Ozone (O3), Benzene,Toulene, Xylene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing suicide rates with D3.js</title>
      <link>/posts/analyzing-suicide-rates-with-d3-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/analyzing-suicide-rates-with-d3-js/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I am going to create a simple Stacked bar chart using D3.js (a Javascript library for data visualization) to understand suicide rates by Region and Gender for the period 1985-2016.
Here is the link to the dataset.
You might ask me, why use D3.js for creating such simple charts, as much easier tools are available. You are right. D3.js is an overkill for such a simple chart. But, the reason behind using D3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being an introvert</title>
      <link>/posts/being-an-introvert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/being-an-introvert/</guid>
      <description>I don’t want to bore you with the technical definition of introvert. Rather, I would like to take you through a journey of how an introvert thinks, feels, works which makes you ponder over what it is being an introvert.
My first taste of understanding the definition of introversion came from Susan Cain after listening to her Ted talk (video below). By the way, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read her book Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking, please give it a read, you won&amp;rsquo;t regret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is your Learning Style?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-your-learning-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-is-your-learning-style/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered why you weren’t able to concentrate in a class?
Your thoughts wander about everywhere from plants, water droplets, sky, milky way, universe….. the moment you start listening to a lecture. Generally, people have different levels of concentration. Few people could concentrate for 10 min and few could concentrate for hours together. This brings us to a point, what makes us different? I would say, it’s all about how our brains are wired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is a Data Visualization Engineer?</title>
      <link>/posts/who-is-a-data-visualization-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/who-is-a-data-visualization-engineer/</guid>
      <description>To answer simply, Data Visualization Engineer is someone who knows how to present data and story tell to drive the point home.
Let’s discuss what skills one should have to enjoy being in this role:
  When you look at data especially messy data, your eyes should lit up and your fingers should start working already to clean and process data at hand.
  When someone explains a problem, you kick start the process by doing research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>